Guide to the Marco Luccio Drypoint Etchings 2008, 2013 PR 409
New-York Historical Society
Marco Luccio drypoint etchings
2008, 2013
New-York Historical Society
Luccio, Marco, 1969-
PR 409
2 Linear feet in one flat file
14 drypoint etchings made in 2008 and 2013 by Australian artist Marco Luccio. All are of New York City scenes, principally of the built environment.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically.
Biographical / Historical
Marco Luccio, born in 1969, is an award-winning Australian artist whose work is held in over 40 public and corporate collections, including the National Gallery of Australia, the Museum of the City of New York, and the New York Public Library. In 2008, Luccio visited New York, drawing a series entitled "Cityscapes of New York."
Conditions Governing Access
Available by advance appointment only. To schedule an appointment, contact the Print Room Librarian at printroom@nyhistory.org.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
"Chinatown" and "Cranes" were gifts of the artist in 2013. The 2013 prints were gifts of the artist in 2016. Donation information for the 2008 print ""Lights, Cars and the Flatiron" is unavailable, but was likely a gift of the artist around 2013-2016.
Scope and Contents
The collection includes 14 drypoint etchings made in 2008 and 2013 by artist Marco Luccio. One of the prints "New York and Central Park" is in three sections. All are of New York City scenes, principally of the built environment. The 2008 prints are from Luccio's series "Cityscapes of New York." The container list below includes the titles of all etchings in the collection. Their size ranges from approximately 15"x11" to 29"x20".
New York (N.Y.) -- Pictorial works.; Cityscapes (representations); Drypoints (prints)
- "Chinatown" (24/25, signed), 2008 (Folder FF-1)
- "Cranes on 29th Street" (10/25, signed), 2008 (Folder FF-1)
- "Lights, Cars and the Flatiron" (10/25, signed), 2008 (Folder FF-1)
- "New York and Central Park" in 3 sections (7/50), 2013 (Folder FF-1)
- "Nightime in New York" (7/50, signed), 2013 (Folder FF-1)
- "Crowds and the Flatiron" (A/P, signed), 2013 (Folder FF-1)
- "Chrysler, Pipes and the Queensboro Bridge" (6/50, signed), 2013 (Folder FF-1)
- Untitled [Grand Central Station] (7/50, signed), 2013 (Folder FF-1)
- "Blimp and the New Yorker" (A/P, signed), 2013 (Folder FF-1)
- "The Manhattan Bridge" (6/50, signed), 2013 (Folder FF-1)
- "Empire from the Chrysler Building" (7/50, signed), 2013 (Folder FF-1)
- "Freedom Tower" (6/50, signed), [2013] (Folder FF-1)
  Scope and Contents
  Mistakenly dated as 2003
- "The Flatiron From the Side" (A/P, signed), 2013 (Folder FF-1)
- "View from the Sherry Netherland" (9/50, signed), 2013 (Folder FF-1)